for
[Music]
h
pantaloons
[Music]
particles pantaloons
particulars
particular
it's that time of
year porcupine
possum
particular uh
pandas P
[Music]
pandas okay
well there's defin lag in the video
performance when switching between
Windows as just say to move this to a
floating there's a bit of delay
there but I suspect that has to do with
[Music]
um the the two monitors that are that
are um connected to
the
external GPU um are different
resolutions so I think that
[Music]
um
all right so back
to
[Music]
variable
bandwidth
for
h
back
for
[Music]
that's
I had been
practicing practicing that
maneuver for a um comically madeup
period of
time
huh yeah
[Music]
okay so the reason why I'm
procrastinating I have sought out
initially to accomplish a different set
of
tasks um but one thing that's been
bothering me
recently I'll I'll I'll rephrase they'll
say an issue that I've been
experiencing um recently is um video
[Music]
stutter or tearing believe is
the so
um by the by the way apparently if you
have blue
eyes um you are prone to
alcoholism according to one person
I I don't
know something about that sort of
bothers me but anyway it's um this one
of those generalizations I guess
um so yeah screen tearing
um right
now
the host is using the default
Intel driver
[Music]
packages which have not been the most
Cooperative to use at least in my
particular setup
here so what
I'm going to try to do
now is to uh run A
playbook that
will um re yeah it'll remove the Intel
drivers install the
[Music]
xorg I the reference to notes that uh
the the mode setting
[Music]
drivers had better success with those uh
than having to um
specify uh to to
not it's an odd option screen teing uh
needs to be set as an perimeter or an
option to be
false was it
true well anyways we'll find out and
uh
first
[Music]
aome
that's right this is
X I'm I've just recently in uh installed
this particular distribution uh which is
using xfc as uh desktop environment and
I forgot but default delightfully enough
uh it comes configured with the xsf
xfce drop down terminal
uh which I guess I'll do that later
[Music]
but uh this is a
really
surprisingly uh
simple yeah for once I me it um
application media media m
TX I classify it as an application that
you would publish um a stream with your
preferred protocol uh to it which then
um other hosts within the network can
connect to uh to view that Stream So in
this case on the host that is um
streaming to the YouTube Channel using
open broadcast
studio within that
client uh a scene is created with a
media
source as the
RT MP
stream so once I hit start streaming
from the sending
client to the the primary Gateway
[Music]
host
yeah which I I think is particularly um
neat uh the application uh media
MTX uh requires no additional
configuration for this particular setup
to
work uh which is super refreshing as
someone who doesn't know the
particular
um how do I
say
the a video streaming protocols not
familiar not particularly familiar with
those
protocols um but are required for for
tasks such as
these so I think that's really
nice
two
[Music]
three
okay
h
excuse me
Jesus so yeah I really got to get on the
generative
background
music just I
mean I don't
know Lo Loi hipop comes to mind
um which is a hit or miss um sometimes
it kind of
screws screwy sort of
um that off tune
zound I don't know how to describe it so
I'm going to risk violating um some sort
of copyright thing
by finding a example an example of what
I'm uh kind of yammering on here
about uh
L Christmas H sure let's
uh that the
speakers
would be a to hear that
[Music]
okay
he
[Music]
h
[Applause]
[Music]
these
oh
[Music]
right
he
[Music]
well that that that was nice
yeah I should put that on the
uh back on the
[Music]
um
so yeah that was um a Christmas uh
themed
[Music]
that's that's Loi
girl and her and her
[Music]
cat you didn't notice there but she got
distracted by the beat coming in just a
little too um not uh how do you say in
time
um that's just me though I find that
stuff
distracting ah all right uh I give up my
dream of being a
DJ you happy now
[Music]
dad
well it's silly
I not that I terribly mind the creative
process but I I can't just put on
background music um
that might be slightly
familiar uh otherwise
um that part of the video gets muted
um with a little notification of um oh
how is it
phrased some sort of copyright
infringement
right
huh and it's just
[Music]
annoying I
me um all right I'll one I one more
try this is labeled uh
[Music]
midi uh by uh sir Cedric the
Honus all right
[Music]
oh
the
[Music]
hunting
space
[Music]
Benjo
d
[Music]
in the
xorg xorg
[Music]
rooll right right now this this
repository I'm sort of in the in the
middle of
um
refactoring uh
trying to
um get as
much of the dro agnostic configurations
as I can into this particular collection
um but within this
role um where is
it
ah packages are installed
[Music]
which is
great so I have two hosts one running a
variant of Arch Linux called Endeavor
o another a variant of Dean or MX Linux
called a v
[Music]
Linux uh so two distinguishing features
of these hosts um
the Endeavor
[Music]
OS the host running Endeavor
OS um is using I3 Window
Manager when running a v Linux at
current is using
xfce as the window uh desktop
environment excuse
me which uh so far has been a uh quite
an enjoyable uh experience in terms of
um an aesthetically pleasing workflow
there's
[Music]
um an array of system
tools that make a lot of the
configurations easier to get to uh
really nice features like the ability to
create a live ISO of the currently
running system that's a really
uh how do I
say I'm going to say neat really
neat
feature
um takes a lot of the uh leg work on of
creating a custom
ISO with a configured
distribution now to be quite honest I'm
just sort of
uh clicked on some things just
clicking but uh it's a it's a so far
it's been a enjoyable
experience
right away it's a bit of a struggle
coming from uh a keyboard driven
keyboard driven
workflow
um and a tying Window Manager uh but
those things can can be adjusted in
[Music]
xfce for example
um terminal
oh see okay so it remembered its La uh
last location and then it's set to snap
against other windows which is really
nice
I have this I think
unreasonable uh sort of um you know it's
it's definitely
classifiable as um
paranoid but uh paranoid thinking anyway
um but
uh even having my name displayed
on public anything makes the back of my
mind go hey is that safe and I I always
have to remind myself
yes at this
point anything terrible that would
happen through that
Medium wouldn't be I wouldn't assume
random
randomized anyways getting off topic
here
[Music]
Okay
so
[Music]
so all
right
[Music]
I had a whole lot of
like really
[Music]
um there's a lot of like cool things to
do
[Music]
with what we call a
computer it's that word still sounds
wrong in my head for what it
is um
[Music]
but or I guess it's a workstation I can
just call it old work
[Music]
station
okay so in my head what I'm trying to
think of is a um a variant of a
character the the the
classical just movs me the wrong way the
class IAL uh burnout
Stoner so reason why I'm mulling this
over and over is
that in a
conventional uh from a conventional
perspective I'm just kind of stoned
right now and I I've lost um a
significant amount of Mo motivation in
terms of getting a specific task done
done is this still a thing even I don't
I don't even think it is I I bet I
detached from that a long time ago
[Music]
um so anyways what I'm trying to think
of is a new way of framing this cuz I'm
not clearly burnt out but I am enjoyably
stoned um and typically I do enjoy
um working
[Music]
with software just any software in
general
[Music]
um but then I started listening to this
uh haunting space
[Music]
bjo
m
[Music]
well one one thing that I'm thinking
about is trying to
um explain certain habits and behaviors
[Music]
um to help perhaps maybe fill
in perspective fill out fill out
perspective um it's a difficult place to
get to in life if if you go looking for
[Music]
it which
yeah I would I would doubt any of us
truly do go go looking for
[Music]
it oh right so
um besides all
that
[Music]
all right the
um the Intel video
[Music]
drivers
h
[Music]
well I I procrastinate on um this
delightful
THS
[Music]
um as I find the the quality of my
productive output
is I suppose subjectively but
better if I don't go into a task that
I'm not particularly excited about with
a oh I got to get this
done um and just you know try to hammer
it out as quickly as
possible
um it's
funny the nice part about that is is
that one wasn't really a conscious
Choice by uh through my thought process
it was a matter of uh the aging process
sort of
limiting the uh ability to even go about
things that
way where I I look back at the output I
go hm okay there is um it's wide in
scope which is you know
um I consider you know a good thing but
it's also
um
disorganized I would say
[Music]
um and I I believe that sort of
scattered output is a result of certain
pressures uh that we all
feel in regards to our productivity in
the amount of time that we feel
productive
[Music]
always you know I'm always trying to be
more descriptive than our previous
generation was able to be so when I
think about things of oh you know it
just sort of works itself out in the
end it's an oddly true enough
phrase to a listener
uh of who hears that phrase spoken by
someone who has experience enough to
know what that phrase represents and
then use that phrase in a proper
context it's it it does a disservice to
just leave it at that without further
explanation cuz it's it's a human
phenomenon it's not cultural it's not
State it's not uh you
know border determined it's everyone
goes through
this
um oh yeah and and I'm waiting
[Music]
just waiting for chat GDP
or whatever next thing
um well that's certainly not ready yet
for that for this sort of thing I'm
waiting for the models that are
um how do I
say that can fulfill any fantasy or whim
that I have at any given moment at any
particular time uh without
um
Direction I figured that should
[Music]
be next third quarter at the
latest I love the smart move would have
been Christmas
but
[Music]
oh
I'm serious though
um the best
work is not reflected unfortunately it's
not truly
reflected sorry
um by find yourself find
[Music]
yourself
besides radical free speech and all that
it's just now occurring to me
um at least today again
[Music]
that oh it'll come back hold on a
second
I have to be uh what I think is an oddly
an odd amount of dishonest about uh who
I uh choose or how I choose to rep
represent myself as a
person
um I find that rather
unfortunate it's an aspect of it's just
it's an aspect of the environment it's
not um a grand
conspiracy um it's a
result sadly
enough what that means is You know
despite the alleviation of
fear despair is a classic um notion
that's still around and
um no more or rest more or less relevant
than any other time in our existence
[Music]
distance
yeah I guess it's a it's um not I would
say common but it's somewhat of a
stereotype of the um disgruntle
philosophical uh Linux uh computer
operator um Andor
programmer
[Laughter]
uh as most as most part of me tries to
actively uh make that person or persons
um question at least why they go about
things that way at least if not for a
small time to uh enjoy the
relaxation
[Music]
cuz if you believe in stuff in the year
2023 in the land of
America um it's a tough
life it's not a terrible life it's not
an atrociously tragic life traumatic
Etc but it's not great it's not it's not
great
and see it takes a huge amount of kind
of weird energy to take what's
essentially starting off as like uh a
rage
[Music]
of you know the rage as a result of
giving attention to the Human
Condition it's an unexp ected kind of go
nowhere
feeling I mean don't get me wrong it
feels
good I don't understand that um alls I
know is it can hurt
people to allow yourself to
consistently
um let the anger Cho the words in that
part of the
brain that does that sort of
[Music]
thing
EX
[Music]
I suppose my my sort of sort of one take
on my
experience is that
um it's really hard to focus
on
life
and still find the motivation to
type which is just my um attempt at
revity and what is typically a long
winded uh set of shared
[Music]
experiences I
this
I'm always trying to think of ways to be
funny which is uh then when I say always
I mean like I don't know every 3 to 5
minutes I do my best it's a huge kind of
like pain in the ass like actually it's
a tremendous pain in the ass I I cannot
express enough how
un um
oversimplified
the um the railway system is in the
upper Northern uh Peninsula States it's
[Music]
crazy that thing upper North what it
upper North Peninsula States uh I don't
think I'm not sure it's a thing
um there's one Peninsula State
anyways
[Music]
um
oh the the Monumental task
um of making a habit of not using
absolute
words um like always never all the time
um it's another one
um well I I guess
that's
a good set of examples um it's
surprisingly just though that
little twist in what is truly
intended in terms of the thought
really it it affects things
that I wish I can describe better cuz
it's subtle but
profound
why he always does that I always do this
no you
don't typically anybody spends a very
oddly small fraction of amount of time
doing
anything and this is weird right like
the uh at least to me to think about it
in these terms
[Music]
uh you know can't see it when we're by
ourselves or not even necessarily like
alone but within familiar space um when
we go
outside uh to interact with the
environment in our communities we have
to act differently than we do when we
are by ourselves or otherwise familiar
space
um and and the depictions through um
I'll leave it at media television movies
etc etc and I think paints a very narrow
[Music]
picture and while some of that you know
I know is designed for good intent well
intention uh I suppose um Safeguard
reasons
um I don't know if it doesn't doesn't
end up making the general listener of
the
message at a disadvantage in terms of
the amount of
information they have available to
compare their entire experience their
entire waking living dreaming whatever
EXP experience not dead you know
whatever um the whole
[Music]
thing I believe and yes I'm one of those
uh I don't know how it's considered
these days but like uh it's like
pretentious I think like oh yeah I don't
want I don't really watch TV anymore you
know that's that sort of thing yeah well
also one of those people um but I I only
bring it up CU it's an important uh fact
of
an to to know that I'm generally unaware
if you know it a c censorship is still
what it was oh uh you know it was like
five six years ago you know I don't know
if that's progressed at all soz I didn't
kept up on it so I generally speak in
ignorance on that topic and I'm believe
that's how you're supposed to sound when
you're um when you don't know something
or
otherwise
unaware
um but it took me a moment to recall
that it's only been a short amount of
time I doubt it's changed that much
[Music]
um
I don't think it's within our control I
think that that control is
lost whatever day it was that they
plugged the internet in
together which uh Jesus that's been like
30 some OD
years yeah so
[Music]
if I say too much more than that uh then
I have to take a
position no it's not it turns out to not
be worth it in this I want to say day
and age but current
time which
just conveniently enough now
um
we we need better phrases for expressing
these sort of things it's sort of funny
I miss the space balls routine when it's
then now Nows when however that went you
know hilarious but now it's like
[Music]
using the same words to try to
describe two different experiences and
then you know like why is it why is it
confusing that's why um one of one of
the reasons um that's that's the one I I
focus on I
don't well sometimes I do I try to
pretend to know everything only in the
sense of being confident in the things
that I am saying um which is just you
know knowing things and such a weird um
thing I'm so I'm 43 I was
born in 1980 I don't know why that's
relevant but it came to
[Music]
mind which then distracted my thought
process this and I've now U lost that
particular thought somewhere back over
here I'm guessing but will somehow I can
only say through electrical impulses uh
give back to the center that processes
it um you know in conscious or um
immediate
attention um which I think is neat I
think it's a neat
[Music]
uh I've been saying that too much um
for
[Music]
is
well let's see I do wish I had a bit
more energy to
[Music]
um in my mind it wants to insert a some
sort of humor there since I didn't
really have anything of substance right
away was kind of one to like
that and so there's always something for
the you know to fill in for what what it
wants to to be humor
it's uh it's it it is it's a I don't
know it's
uh it's the part of the thought process
that's doing that and is uh wonderful it
really
is I don't know what exact Condition
it's diagnosed as
uh I don't want to say these days I'm
not from
1943 but it it's um yeah I would have to
I would have
to uh share
that yeah again and again again and I
don't really want to do that actually
reason um sorry I didn't mean to be
defensive at anything just
uh sharing does that to people
sometimes
that's why I like stealing
[Music]
things iry
anyways it's that kind
of wa minute what is
[Music]
that
o
right right but I know it's a
thing it's um some sort of identity
disorder
[Music]
um which I uh
for uh editorial purposes I happen to
believe it's a byproduct of our culture
more than an inherited Mental
Illness but that is the least popular
opinion in any sort of um commercial
Endeavor
[Music]
so oh no was a thing I wanted to
click on oh
[Music]
yes this interface it really is it it's
really easy to um is it on the interface
it is excellent um it's it is really
easy to sort of um
move the uh desired
um
uh well it's a representation of a task
right application
um in other words uh the workflow is
it's it's a nice change of pace uh from
the keyboard
driven feels kind of flowy where the Keo
Dr feels just more like uh
rmic so the music makes sense
[Music]
um
oh
right well I don't like all the labels
cuz they're all attached with uh
opinions and
[Music]
it's
oh disassociative identity disorder
that's the that's what it's called Uh
disintegration of normal integrated M
Moder systems
compartmentalization an alter of
Consciousness Detachment and a defense
mechanism that's funny
um 83 % of the behavior defense
Mech oh that's
funny the last definition basically
reflects the function of the first two
definitions okay the last
definition basically reflects the
function the last definition basically
reflects the functions of the first two
definitions now I'm going to play a
little game with myself where I try to
de am I really stoned or is this a
poorly written
[Music]
sentence I'm sorry I guess that sounds
rude not poorly
um H I forget what it's supposed to
be but it's U meant to be
polite Believe It or
Not unfortunately I do not have enough
context to fully understand or respond
to your statement so that tells me
something right there I'm usually pretty
good at getting Claud to talk to me so
but now's going to lecture me for for
some reason to have a productive
discussion would be helpful if you would
provide full context what were the
previous sub you gave what was the final
third okay slow down Claude
okay like what the
I ask was it a question or a
statement it was a
statement and it just
onslaught
of uh well in the context of a database
response to a query uh it is a thorough
clarification of the
[Music]
information that it's trying to
produce for the
[Music]
uh person using the
tool and now I have to do more
work I didn't mean to copy and paste it
just like that last two yeah hold
[Music]
on
start there unfortunately I cannot
definitively State whether generative
and functional grammars are fully align
with the syntactical standards of
commonly spoken
that's good it didn't chat GTP me so
chat GTP would have tried to me
here which don't uh you
know
[Laughter]
I it is also much better at
um defining layouts defining outlines uh
summarizing
um but yeah it
lies um but anyway it's it's an OD
restriction that is is obviously Up For
Debate as to how much it should be
restricted restricted excuse me you know
who should restrict it is it the user
responsibility is it the company
responsibility you know that whole thing
um I don't know what we've learned from
every re how do I say uh uh all the
other sectors in our um
economy I'm just I'm trying to think of
a a PO a more polite way of saying um
this is not a new problem and a lot of a
lot of it seems to be uh being treated
like it is and it's um it's hard it's
hard to try to figure out ways to be um
sort of uh
you're kind of raising the signal hey uh
we need to kind of
uh really really
assess uh how how we use and how we
using these these
tools these fantastically useful
tools okay so it does uh does uh it
neglects to make an attempt at pulling
pulling together an answer that's good
um although what I what I do like about
uh gbt chat GBP that when it does you
that there are instances where in that
[Music]
um I don't know I don't I don't know
what to call it lies seems to much
uh it needs to be a a a more computery
word I guess it can't this one can't be
part of that
metaphor but you know anyways um so I'm
I'm just trying to say that if you run
into that sort of thing uh obviously
it's probably not the desired result but
it's not necessarily dismissive of just
something that's wrong um it does uh
anyways um which I but then it it does
then just take take the extra bandwidth
to um you know
layout let's
see as the listen to this
reasoning
gives is this is a this is a complex
issue with ongoing debate among
[Music]
lists it's like oh I didn't I
technically didn't know that
so
um oh okay so my question was very
specific to something else and it
replied withfor cannot depend State
whether generative function of grammars
are fully aligned with the syntactical
standards of commonly spoken English
which is by the way kind just basically
a
sentence any it's
uh how do I say um commonly spoken
English is sort of um the semi-ironic
part
um not for honestly not for humor sake
for um for the sake of how do I say at
the end of that thought I go oh okay
what I'm trying to really ascertain here
is whether or not this person who is uh
representing an institution that
is publishing information in what is
known to be and this this sucks to say
cuz I know it's not intentional I do
believe that but I do believe it is
still used in the sense of um you know
that's what they
do it's not to them it's not about this
just I have to give that very loud
disclaimer it's not to them it's not
about this so therefore you know it's
not something to hold against but
um
[Music]
it's um using this tool is very
powerful uh to put it
simply a
sentence
misworded
misunderstood otherwise
[Music]
misinterpreted read
by an overly
enthusiastic person trying to
help who then dedicates their life to
studying some sort of
uh some sort of medicinal path I
suppose huh and that person can then
inherit that sort of
[Music]
um information and do significant
damage to
lives people's lives like yours like
[Music]
mine so it's a hard task to critique
these things with kind of the framework
of uh Where Do We
Begin you know uh so uh the only thing I
believe I can do in my
lifetime uh is to do my bus to use what
you know is our version of like a wheel
or something of that to that effect or a
light bulb if you will I guess uh you
know and sort of due diligence to use a
tool that makes a lot of this type of
work uh just much
easier truly uh it it is something just
indeed remarkable
um but the languages that are used to
being Express that are used to express
uh you know so much
[Music]
of circumstance in idual circumstance is
incorrect it turns out to be
syntactically grammatically
incorrect not by my assessment that is
an assessment based on um people's uh
how do you say qualified FK people's um
pointing out of the fact that oh yeah
English is based on a set of
[Laughter]
rules you know um that's fair very
important uh in
understanding it's supposed to be like
hopeful it's a it's a hopeful message
it's not it's a bit of it's my
frustration of not being able to
articulate
[Music]
uh is this one I hope
not I'm just hoping I haven't gotten all
the way through this yet that there is
no sweeping
generalizations that's what I'm
concerned
[Music]
with is when we
get when we explore these sort of things
we feel that a sense of
importance and unfortunately what comes
along with that is a very persistent
sense of
certainty and then
excitement uh at the at the uh you
know it's a conditioned response but the
excitement at the prospect of future
recognition or acceptance or
validation
a lot of people's lines have been
damaged because prominent figures in
institutional
positions um wanted to succeed just too
a little too
much which I hear myself say that out
loud it sounds it sounds a bit vague
it's not really um CU what I'm trying to
do is not to offend but I'm also trying
not to um leave any detail
out and that's really hard to
do um growing up on television
programming
um which I love that's what it's called
I I truly do it's
[Music]
um
it makes sense right like why we're
always so excited about everything
especially in
[Music]
America it's it's just something that
has developed as a society over 2 300
years as a result
of
um a sort of move away from oppressing
or repressing
[Music]
ourselves it's also
yeah struggled could not comprehend the
logic of her
maltreatment
that's that that to me in hopefully
terms that are just an attempt at
getting you know the most number of
people to
agree on the words but um could not
comprehend the logic of her Mal
treatment those so that's so picture two
people engaged in uh
in engaged two people
engaged and they're in a disagreement a
conflict about something
right so a fascinating study about 68
months ago uh from a set of
neuroscientists they discover with their
Mr functional MRIs um
uh visualization technology uh that when
people are are engaged in a meaningful
um scenario situation conversation
meeting as it were
um electrical signals in the brain light
up in the same areas of the brain in the
two people suggesting that some sort of
synchronization is taking place when two
people are engaged in you know connected
thought um and that like you know Cosmic
Consciousness connected thought like you
know hey do you see that stapler over
there uh yes yes I do too uh you know
when you're engaged in that sort of
mutual agreement of something um you
know the the they so they see now
there's um the similar regions of the
brain light up in in the two
individuals so what I think is happening
in these extreme cases where you have
one side who is the practitioner trying
to figure out the problem trying to
diagnose the problem driven intelligent
um some of that's ego driven some of
that is pure altruism It's a combination
of both that um you know none of us are
properly trained now growing up
um it's two it's two parts of the brain
two sections of the brain that see the
world differently based on the
information those sections of the brain
receive
right so that is what is sort I would
call it a a Mel sync or a Miss sync or
something something uh inverse to sync
synchronization um
where yeah I what I cannot comprehend
why you are treating me this way and the
other side is I cannot comprehend why
you are acting this way and those are
two people
engaged in uh what they they coin as
brain
synchrony um with
malaligned function sections of the
brain processing information incorrectly
when it's when it's being processed
correctly there is no question about
what that is what is that there's no
question when when it's in um in
alignment how much influence we have
over that alignment is really what
the problem I guess it's not it's more
than an
issue um
is I I I can only say from personal
experience it's um there this is a
higher level of
degree that we have to
control whether or not we can you know
purposely
engage and have
everything you know going
[Music]
well
but that is an observ ation of a um both
personal and
um you know un passionately tried my
best to be as objective as anyone can be
um but um you
[Music]
know
oh yeah and certainly Taco Bell is not
nearly as um good of quality of an
experience as it was in
[Music]
1998 that was the golden year of that
particular food
experience and they know it they know it
they're sitting on
that hot medium and Mild Taco Bell money
and they don't really need to try
anymore which I I as a human I don't
blame
them as a member of society I'm
enraged yes just stop just stop doing
that you don't need that anymore we
don't need that anymore we can free up
that resource those people do not want
to be doing that kind of work
robots don't want to be programmed to be
doing that kind of work
work and maybe I don't know just
something different just something
different how about start
there oh that's too much then do nothing
that's the second best option and it is
pretty good
[Music]
actually that is asking a lot I
understand that um
[Music]
um my only suggestion is a 40-year-old
is drugs try drugs I don't
[Music]
know
oh
[Music]
Che